A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1998-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1998-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.011
This collection consists of 27,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred on 2001 August 27.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by John Thomas Casteen, the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1998-1999; seldom used permanent files, 1990-1999); and, committee files, 1975-1999.
Organization
SERIES I: General Files, 1998-1999 Boxes 1-47
SERIES II: Seldom Used Permanent Files, 1990-1999 Boxes 48-57
SERIES III: Committee Files, 1975-1999 Boxes 58-60
SERIES IV: Restricted Files, 1983- 2000 Boxes 61-63
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - "A" Miscellaneous (1-5 of 6) 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - "A" Miscellaneous (6 of 6) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--General (Restricted) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Law (Restricted) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Medical (Restricted) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs--General 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs--Woodson Institute (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education (1 of 2) 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education (2 of 2) 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology--General (Restricted) 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions--General A-Z (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Architecture--General 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Art 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Arts, Planning, and Development (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Assessment, Planning, and Studies--General 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Associated, Western Universities--General 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Association of Academic Health Centers 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges and Universities--General 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities (4 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Association of Governing Boards--General (1 of 2) 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Association of Governing Boards--General (2 of 2) 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Astronomy--General 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--General (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--ACC (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--ECFA (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--Jones, Jeff (Restricted) 1993-1997 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--NCAA (1 of 7) 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Athletics--NCAA (2-5 of 7) 1998-1999 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--NCAA (6-7 of 7) 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Attorney General (State)--General (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Auditor Internal--General (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts--General 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - Bachelor of Interdisciplinary Studies--General 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - Bayly Museum 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Biology--General 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Business and Finance--General (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Business and Finance--General Updates (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Business and Finance--Planning and Budget Committee (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Business Operations--General (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 8) 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (3-5 of 8) 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (6-8 of 8) 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Career Planning and Placement--General 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Cavalier Daily--General 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Casteen, John T.--General 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Casteen, John T.--Personal Letters/Cards 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Center for Advanced Studies 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Center for Innovative Technology--General 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Charlottesville, City of--General 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Charlottesville, City of--Planning: Coordination Council 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Classics, Department of 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Clinch Valley College--General (4 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 12)
  - College of Arts and Sciences--General 1998-1999 (Box 12)
  - Comptroller (State)--General 1998-1999 (Box 12)
  - Condolences--General 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - College Board--General 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - Commerce--General 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - Congress--General 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - CHEA--National Policy Board (1-2 of 4) 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - CHEA--National Policy Board (3-4 of 4) 1998-1999 (Box 14)
  - CHEA--Transfer Initiative 1998-1999 (Box 14)
  - Continuing Education--General (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 14)
  - 15
  - Council of Presidents--General (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 15)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1998-1999 (Box 15)
  - Darden Graduate School--General 1998-1999 (Box 15)
  - Development--General (4 folders) 1999 (Box 16)
  - Drama, Department of--General 1998-1999 (Box 16)
  - D-General 1998-1999 (Box 16)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1998-2000 (Box 16)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Economics--General 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - U.S. Department of Education 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Education--General 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Educational Testing Service--General 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--General 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Engineering and Buildings (State)--General 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - English--General 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Enrollment 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Environmental Sciences--General 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - Equal Opportunity Office 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (1of 7) 1998-1999 (Box 17)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (2-6 of 7) 1998-1999 (Box 18)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (7 of 7) 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Facilities Management-Projects Status Reports (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Faculty--Faculty Letters (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences--General 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Faculty Violence Prevention Fund--General and National Advisory Committee (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - (Box 19)
  - Financial Aid to Students--General 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Flowerdew 100 Foundation 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Food Services--General (Dining) 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly--Legislation 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly--General (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly--Senate Finance Committee 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly--House Appropriations Committee 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly--Legislative Summaries (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - General Counsel--General 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - General Services--General 1998-1999 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants (1-4 of 11) 1998-1999 (Box 21)
  - Gifts and Grants (5-8 of 11) 1998-1999 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants (9-11 of 11) 1998-1999 (Box 23)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs--General 1998-1999 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Administration 1998-1999 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Committee and Trade (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 23)
  - Governor's Office--Education (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 24)
  - Governor's Office--Finance 1998-1999 (Box 24)
  - Governor's Office--Natural Resources 1998-1999 (Box 24)
  - Governor's Office--Photographs 1998-1999 (Box 24)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 24)
  - History--General 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Honor System--General 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Housing--General 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Human Resources--General 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Information Technology--State 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Information Technology and Communications 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - International Students-General 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Invitations to Inaugurations 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Invitations to Social Events (1-3 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Invitations to Social Events (4-5 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 26)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1998-1999 (Box 26)
  - Jefferson, Thomas Memorial Foundation--General 1998-1999 (Box 26)
  - Jefferson Scholars 1998-1999 (Box 27)
  - "K" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 27)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1998-1999 (Box 27)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1998-1999 (Box 28)
  - Law--General 1998-1999 (Box 28)
  - Library--General 1998-1999 (Box 28)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 8) 1998-1999 (Box 28)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (4-8 of 8) 1998-1999 (Box 29)
  - Major Events, Office of--General 1998-1999 (Box 29)
  - Management and Budget (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 29)
  - Mariner's Museum 1998-1999 (Box 29)
  - Mariner's Museum (5 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center--General (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center--Health Sciences Council (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center--Hospital 1998-1999 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center--Medical School 1998-1999 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center--Nursing 1998-1999 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center--Personal 1998-1999 (Box 31)
  - Miller Center 1998-1999 (Box 31)
  - Music-General 1998-1999 (Box 31)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (1-4 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 31)
  - 32
  - "N" Miscellaneous (5 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 32)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--General 1998-1999 (Box 32)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--Green Circulars (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 32)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--Committee on International Exchange (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 32)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--Board on Oceans and Atmosphere (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 32)
  - National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA) (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 32)
  - National Policy Board--CHEA (1-5 of 6) 1998-1999 (Box 33)
  - National Policy Board--CHEA (6 of 6) 1998-1999 (Box 34)
  - National Science Foundation--General 1998-1999 (Box 34)
  - New England Education Loan Marketing--General--Nellie Mae (4 folders) 1992-1998 (Box 34)
  - Nellie Mae Meetings (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 35)
  - Newcomb Hall--General 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1998-2000 (Box 36)
  - Oak ridge Associated Universities--General 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - "P" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - Parking and Transportation--General--State 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - Parking and Transportation--General--University 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - Personnel and Training (State)--General 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - Philosophy--General 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - Physics--General 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - Planning--General 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Planning-UVA--General 1998-2000 (Box 37)
  - Planning and Budget--State 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Provost-Vice Provost for Research 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Provost--General 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - President's Senior Cabinet Meetings--General 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Virginia 2020--General 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Virginia 2020--International/Global Committee 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Virginia 2020--Arts Commission 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Virginia 2020--Public Service and Outreach 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Virginia 2020--Science and Technology Committee 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - Virginia 2020--Talking Points/Speeches 1998-1999 (Box 37)
  - UVA Rector--Provost 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Vice President for Research and Public Service--Gene Black 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Psychology--General 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous--General 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Qual Choice 1998 (Box 38)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Real Estate Foundation--General 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Recommendations--A-Z 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Registrar-General 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Religious Studies--General 1998-1999 (Box 38)
  - Request for Nominations 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - Research and Public Service--General 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - ROTC--Army 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - ROTC--Navy (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - ROTC--General 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - Rotunda Society 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 7) 1998-1999 (Box 39)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (4-7 of 7) 1998-1999 (Box 40)
  - Sorensen Institute for Political Leadership 1998-1999 (Box 40)
  - Senate University 1998-1999 (Box 40)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS)--General (1 of 4) 1998-1999 (Box 40)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS)--General (2-4 of 4) 1998-1999 (Box 41)
  - State Council on Higher Education (SCHEV) (1-2 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 41)
  - State Council on Higher Education (SCHEV) (3-5 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - State Council on Higher Education (SCHEV)--Research Notes (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - State Council on Higher Education (SCHEV)--Council Notes (empty) 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - State Department Education--General 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - Student Affairs--General 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - Student Affairs--Fraternities 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - Student Affairs--Sororities 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - Student Affairs--Dean of Students Search 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - Student Council--General 1998-1999 (Box 42)
  - Summer Session--General 1998-1999 (Box 43)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 43)
  - Treasurer--State--General 1998-1999 (Box 43)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 43)
  - United Way--General 1998-1999 (Box 44)
  - University Research Association--General 1998-1999 (Box 44)
  - University of Virginia Foundation 1998-1999 (Box 44)
  - University Press--General 1998-1999 (Box 44)
  - University Relations--News Office--General 1998-1999 (Box 44)
  - University Police--General 1998-1999 (Box 44)
  - University of Virginia Investment Company--General (2 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 45)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 45)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1998-1999 (Box 46)
  - Virginia Business Higher Education Council--General (1-2 of 3) 1998-1999 (Box 46)
  - Virginia Business Higher Education Council--General (3 of 3) 1998-1999 (Box 47)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film--General 1998-1999 (Box 47)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review--General 1998-1999 (Box 47)
  - Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service--General 1998-1999 (Box 47)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1998-1999 (Box 47)
- Series II: Seldom Used Permanent Files
  - "Y" Miscellaneous--General 1998-1999 (Box 48)
  - "Z" Miscellaneous--General 1998-1999 (Box 48)
  - ACE-Fellows Program--Byyny, Dick-Recommendations (2 folders) 1993-1994 (Box 48)
  - Athletics--Carquest Bowl 1996 (Box 48)
  - Athletics--Pep Band (Letters) (2 folders) 1993-1994 (Box 48)
  - Bice, R.C. (4 folders) 1968-1999 (Box 49)
  - Development--Capital Campaign IV (1-2 of 6) 1996 (Box 49)
  - Development-Capital Campaign IV (3-6 of 6) 1996 (Box 50)
  - EEO/AA Brown, Simon 1995-1997 (Box 50)
  - FOIA--Freedom of Information Act (1-2 of 4) 1974-1991 (Box 50)
  - FOIA--Freedom of Information Act (3-4 of 4) 1974-1991 (Box 51)
  - Governor--A.L. Philpott Manufacturing Research Center II (3 folders) 1997 (Box 51)
  - Governor Allen-Executive Orders (2 folders) 1994-1997 (Box 52)
  - Information Technology and Communication--Polley McClure (2 folders) 1994-1998 (Box 52)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Advisory Board III (1 of 3) 1987-1994 (Box 52)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Advisory Board III (2-3 of 3) 1987-1994 (Box 53)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Board--Newsletter 1984-1989 (Box 53)
  - Lawrence Lewis Jr. 1992-1995 (Box 53)
  - Medical Center--Hospital Advisory Board 1982-1989 (Box 53)
  - Miller Center--Ken Thompson 1983-1990 (Box 53)
  - National Policy Board--CHEA (4 folders) 1998 (Box 54)
  - Provost--Vice Provost for Research 1993-1997 (Box 54)
  - Visitors--General (1-5 of 7) 1997-1998 (Box 55)
  - Visitors--General (6-7 of 7) 1997-1998 (Box 56)
  - Visitors--General (2 folders) 1998 (Box 56)
  - Visitor--Cooper, Matthew 1994 (Box 56)
  - Visitor--Dabney, Hovey S. (2 folders) 1990-1998 (Box 57)
  - Visitor--Darden, Joshua P. (2 folders) 1988-1996 (Box 57)
  - Visitor--Hoffler, Daniel A. 1992-1996 (Box 57)
  - Visitor--McNeely, C. Wilson III 1994-1999 (Box 57)
  - Visitors--Omitted Documents (2 folders) 1995 (Box 57)
- Series III: University Committees
  - Visitor-Small, Albert H. (5 folders) 1992-1997 (Box 58)
  - Student member--Robert Schoenvoger--Board of Visitors 1999-2000 (Box 58)
  - Visitors--Summary Sheets 1975-1989 (Box 59)
  - Weather Emergencies (3 folders) 1974-1992 (Box 59)
  - Weather Emergencies--Inclement Weather 1991-1992 (Box 59)
  - Arboretum and Landscape Committee 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Athletics Advisory Council 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Benefits 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Commencement and Convocations 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Subcommittee--Processions 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Subcommittee--Public Occasions 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Commission on Access for Persons with Disabilities 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Financial Aid 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Information Technology 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Master Planning Council 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Libraries Committee 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Judiciary--University Committee 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Names Committee 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Radiation Safety 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Security and General Safety 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Traffic Appeals Committee 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Transportation and Parking 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Undergraduate Admissions 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - University Press of Virginia 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Virginia Status of University Students 1998-1999 (Box 60)
  - Advisory Committee on Women's Concerns 1998-1999 (Box 60)
- Series IV: Restricted Files (Box 61-63)